

CONTACT

judahavery.com

in linkedin.com/in/judahavery

judahbavery@gmail.com

(802)-777-0970

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Unreal Engine 5
- Unreal Blueprint
- Unity
- C#
- Visual Studio
- Maya / Blender
- Confluence
- Jira
- Perforce
- Adobe Suite

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Technical Design
- Systems Design
- Combat Design
- Enemy Design
- Visual Design
- Rapid Prototyping
- Design Documentation
- Strong Design Sense
- Working Under Deadlines

INTERESTS

- Surfing
- Snowboarding & Skiing
- Running & Hiking
- Tabletop Games

SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary designer with AAA experience building gameplay systems and enemy combatants in technically demanding roles within cross-disciplinary teams. Self-driven workflow fueled by a passion for crafting refined, emotionally resonant experiences that leave a lasting impression on players.

EXPERIENCE

Unannounced Project - Santa Monica Studio

Technical Combat Designer | October 2024 - Present

- Combat focused role with an emphasis on crafting enemies that uniquely challenge the player's core combat kit among the enemy cast
- Leverage text based scripting, visual scripting, behavior trees, Maya, and other proprietary tools to rapidly iterate and test solutions
- Collaborating primarily with animators alongside art, audio, encounter design, engineering, production, and departmental leads to meet design goals
- Constantly iterating and acting on feedback from playtests and directors

Unannounced Project - Respawn Entertainment

Combat Designer | December 2023 - October 2024

- Responsible for multiple enemy AI, pitching the initial design, prototyping, and iterating through team feedback and playtesting
- Direct collaboration across departments, especially animation, tweaking enemy attacks, navigation, personality, etc.
- Ownership of multiple combat systems, working extensively with Unreal Blueprint, behavior trees, animation montages, and animation blueprints

Star Wars: Jedi Survivor - Respawn Entertainment

Technical Designer | Shipped Title | August 2022 - December 2023

- Unreal blueprint expert and point of contact for support regarding Unreal 4/5
- Responsible for multiple game systems, unique AI behaviors, UI/UX features, level design features, and more
- Direct collaboration with Level Design, Encounters, Sound Design, Animation, Destruction, UI/UX, QA, Code, and departmental leads/directors
- At the finaling stage, helped to hunt down, reproduce, and solve bugs to bring the game to ship

Star Wars: Jedi Survivor - Respawn Entertainment

Technical Design Intern | May 2022 - August 2022

- Interned while pursuing a bachelors in Game Design, where I was offered an immediate full time role, which I accepted in place of finishing my degree
- · Acted with similar responsibilities to the above role, though smaller in scale

EDUCATION

High School Diploma | Computer Animation & Web Design

Center For Technology, Essex, Vermont | 2017 - 2019

- Started pursuing game design/development through a tech program in my final two years of high school
- Competed in nation-wide game development competitions both years after qualifying through placing 1st in the state